Lowell Thomas Papers
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
- 1. Reel-to-Reel audio tape, 1934 - 1981; 1; Boxes: 1744 - 1818
  - Subseries 1.8: Personalities, 1942 - 1961; 1.8; Boxes: 1775 - 1779
    - Personalities - Interviews, undated (Folder 1778.14, Box 1778)
      Robert Grant interview with H. V. Kaltenborn, Part II USIA/VOA New York, 250 W 57th - Room 1620
    - Personalities - Interviews: Explorer Post 103 to Lowell Thomas, undated (Folder 1778.15, Box 1778)
      Boy Scout Explorer Post 103 Reply and thanks from Post 103 for promo made earlier by Lowell Thomas. Post advisor Bob Brooks speaks first. “Thank You” - French - Hungarian - Italian - Greek - German - Lithuanian - Latin
    - Personalities - Interviews: Werkson, Dibbs, Lamby., undated (Folder 1778.16, Box 1778)
      Tape sent from Basra via TWA. - Greetings from Jack Werkson, Gil Dodds and Doctor Lamby
    - Personalities - Interviews: Pilot film prologue, undated (Folder 1778.17, Box 1778)
      Lowell Thomas Senior - Prologue to pilot film Re: TV news program. Outline of format, general comment
    - Personalities - Interviews: Sir Edmund Hillary, undated (Folder 1778.18, Box 1778)
      Sir Edmund Hillary - projections on Everest expedition. Theory on acclimatization of body - attempt to get permission for climb - 2 cuts - 15 inches per second - 7.5 inches per second
    - Personalities - Interviews: Proposed TV series, undated (Folder 1779.01, Box 1779)
      Lowell Thomas Prologue to preview of proposed TV series. Weekly summary of news - done in conjunction with Sig. Michelson of CBS.
    - Personalities - Interviews: Lowell Thomas/Chase, Tibetan accident, undated (Folder 1779.02, Box 1779)
      Lowell Thomas - interview by Joseph Cummings Chase, Story on accident in Tibet
    - Personalities - Interviews: Victor Berg, Diving mask, undated (Folder 1779.03, Box 1779)
      Victor Berge (Twin track) Side number 1 - diving mask Side number 2 - camping
    - Personalities - Interviews: W.B. Wood, Nepal, undated (Folder 1779.04, Box 1779)
      Return to: W.B. Wood, 942 East 18th Street, Eugene Oregon “Nepal: Little Country with Big Problems”
    - Personalities - Interviews: Lowell Thomas, Cinerama, Reeves, Coop., undated (Folder 1779.05, Box 1779)
      Lowell Thomas “How I started a world revolution” Cinerama - story of Reeves-Cooper Recorded in San Francisco, California
    - Personalities - Interviews: Lowell Thomas, Nat. Arts Club Reel 1, undated (Folder 1779.06, Box 1779)
      Lowell Thomas - Address before members of National Arts Club in New York City. Subject - Out of This World Edited - spliced original
    - Personalities - Interviews: Fireplace night Quaker Hill Country Club, undated (Folder 1779.07, Box 1779)
      Fire place night (stone placement) Quaker Hill Country Club - Lowell Thomas 1) Bert Stevenson 2) Max Thornburg 3) Doctor Maller 4) Wendell Phillips
    - Personalities - Interviews: Lowell Thomas, Oregon Association of Broadcasters, undated (Folder 1779.08, Box 1779)
      Lowell Thomas on Oregon Association of Broadcasters (4 cuts) Local promo - no date From: Oregon Association of Broadcasters P.O. Box 5025, Eugene Oregon
    - Personalities - Interviews: Adm. Bird/Martha Dean program, undated (Folder 1779.09, Box 1779)
      Admiral Byrd excerpt from Martha Dean program
  - Subseries 1.9: Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1949 - 1976; 1.9; Boxes: 1780 - 1783
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, circa 1949 (Folder 1780.01, Box 1780)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1949 Aboard Constellation over Africa en route Kenya, (quality, poor) Impressions while flying around world. Reflections on travel - favorable and not so. Note on death of Stalin
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, 1958 April (Folder 1780.02, Box 1780)
      (Dakar) number 8 Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Jr.
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.03, Box 1780)
      Rio - Reel 1 Feb. 19 Rio diary (number 1 of series done in plane to Dakar)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.04, Box 1780)
      Rio - Reel 2 Rio diary (reel 2 in series done in route to Dakar)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.05, Box 1780)
      Durban Deep Mines - Reel 2 Durban Deep number 2, including flight to Nairobi
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.06, Box 1780)
      Ngorongoro - Nairobi Mar. 23 First part of Diary - Ngorongoro Crater - Their diary to landing Cairo
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.07, Box 1780)
      Reel 1 8 May Diary - Regarding conversations about Peter Aufschnaiter in Delhi
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.08, Box 1780)
      Reel 2, Re: Peter Aufschnaiter more on talks about Peter Aufschnaiter
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.09, Box 1780)
      Reel 2 - Mar. 11, number 2 of diary about Sheikh brothers in Nairobi)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.10, Box 1780)
      Durban Deep Mines - Reel 1 February 28: Dabar to [Jacbury] and reel number 1 or Durban Deep Mine
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1780.11, Box 1780)
      Hpr. 25 Diary Cairo #3 transferred
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.01, Box 1781)
      Timbuktu - reel number 2 of diary on this trip
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.02, Box 1781)
      Diary - Cairo
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.03, Box 1781)
      Diary - Cairo number 2 - transferred (low level)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.04, Box 1781)
      Diary - Beirut to Damascus number 4
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.05, Box 1781)
      Diary - Damascus to Dakar number 5
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.06, Box 1781)
      Diary - (Dakar) number 6, April 27
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.07, Box 1781)
      Diary - Dakar to Bahrain number 9
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.08, Box 1781)
      Diary - India number 10
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.09, Box 1781)
      Diary - Rangoon number 11, April 30
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.10, Box 1781)
      Diary - Timbuktu, Reel 1 Trip from Dakar to Timbuktu - reel 1 of series
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.11, Box 1781)
      Diary - Timbuktu - Reel 3
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.12, Box 1781)
      Diary - (Sheikh brothers, Nairobi), March 10
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Diary, undated (Folder 1781.13, Box 1781)
      Rio - February 3
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. in Iran, 1949 (Folder 1781.14, Box 1781)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr., Tribal Dances, Baktiari
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. in Iran, circa 1949 (Folder 1781.15, Box 1781)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. Iran and Persia music - discussion of wedding feast - William O. Douglas present. Descriptive narration with background S.E. Baktiari - stick dance - clear for 23 seconds - narration - music from rear - “Baktiari”
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. in Iran -sound effects: Streets of Tehran, 1949 (Folder 1781.16, Box 1781)
      1. Street while riding in Taxi 2. Walking along street in front of Bazaar 3. Apple Seller 4. Lottery Ticket Seller 5. Old Blind red-bearded Mullah praying 6. General Sounds - Newspaper vendor 7. Mellon Vendor 8. Walking by many fruit vendors 9. Walking through Mosque with holy man 10. Blacksmith shops 11. Buying apples - vendor’s voice
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. In Iran, 1949 (Folder 1781.17, Box 1781)
      1. Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Shah of Iran - Economic development - skiing - aviation - tourism 2. Repeat of above (poor quality) 3. Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Ambassador Douglas
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interviews Max Thornburg, 1949 (Folder 1781.18, Box 1781)
      Reel 2 of 2 Lowell Thomas, Jr. from Umma Saboon. Persian Gulf interview and Mr. Max Thornburg. Middle East Gov - Hostility toward British - British and American Policy re-evaluation and Aims - Type of Sov. Needed - Stand U.S. should take VOFL programs needed - personal message from Thornburg to Thomas - Note: original recording on paper tape transferred to plastic and numbered “a” Note from media center: This ¼ inch tape appears to be made of paper. We were not able to play it back at all
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interviews Max Thornburg, 1949 (Folder 1782.01, Box 1782)
      Reel 1 of 2 Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Mr. Max Thornburg. Recorded originally on paperback tape at 11mm A’ Saboan in Persian Gulf
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interviews Max Thornburg, 1953 (Folder 1782.02, Box 1782)
      1) Lowell Thomas, Jr. - with Max Thornburg, broadcast May 26, Tuesday, time 4:38 Broadcast insert from Island in the Persian Gulf - Bahrain 2) Continuation of above broadcast - Wednesday may 27, time 4:40
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Interviews Harold Gatty, 1949 (Folder 1782.03, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Harold Gatty (without film 4)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Interviews Harold Gatty, 1949 (Folder 1782.04, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Harold Gatty (without film 3)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Interviews Harold Gatty, 1949 (Folder 1782.05, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Harold Gatty interview (without film 2)
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Interviews Harold Gatty, 1949 (Folder 1782.06, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Interview with Harold Gatty - (without film 1) Note * dual track at 15 inches per second
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Interviews Captain and Mrs. Taylor, undated (Folder 1782.07, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Informal chat with Captain and Mrs. Taylor (without film) 2 of 2
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1949, Captain and Mrs. Taylor, undated (Folder 1782.08, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Informal chat with Captain and Mrs. Taylor (without film) 1 of 2
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. Informal chat with Duke Kahanamoku in Hawaii, 1950 (Folder 1782.09, Box 1782)
      1. Mostly concerned with experiences during Olympic meet 2. Recorded in Hawaii 1950
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1950, Duke Kahanamoku (Folder 1782.10, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. Continued chat with Duke Kahanamoku - Hawaii Recorded in Hawaii 1950
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1950, Duke Kahanamoku (Folder 1782.11, Box 1782)
      Hawaii interview continued 1. Lowell Thomas, Jr. and Duke Kahanamoku, brother Sam, and F. Lana Akana 2. Australia - Surf board - Prince of Wales - swim and seal - motion picture experience - 1925 rescue at Balboa - Sona - more Australian swim meets, New Zealand - Political aspirations 3. Recorded in Hawaii 1950
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1950, Duke Kahanamoku (Folder 1782.12, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr., Duke Kahanamoku and Mr. Ling. Song (15 inches per second) meets Franklin Delano Roosevelt as Governor and President - Marries Laka - First Christian church - number 1 hobby - number of pure Hawaiian in 1951 (12,000) Economic trend - Higher education Recorded in Hawaii
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. 1955 Graduation Address P.C.H.S., 1960 December 6 (Folder 1782.13, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. An address before graduating class at Pawling Central High School - 1955
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. on Alaska, 1960 (Folder 1782.14, Box 1782)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. family from Alaska
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Alaskan King Crab, circa 1961 February (Folder 1782.15, Box 1782)
      1. Sync camera of Lowell Thomas, Jr. - February 10, 1961 NO GOOD - DON’T PRINT!! 2. February 17 - Sync. Scene 1 Take 1 - Fluff at end Scene 1 Take 2 - No good (dog noises) Scene 1 Take 3 - This is best Scene 2 Take 1 - Too serious Scene 2 Take 2 - Best
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. on Alaska, 1961 December29 (Folder 1782.16, Box 1782)
      1. Lowell Thomas, Jr. on Martha Dean program 2. Original edited tape. 3. Copy made and sent to Lowell Thomas, Jr. at Anchorage, January 24, 1962 4. Aired on WOR December 29, 1961
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1962 December 14 (Folder 1782.17, Box 1782)
      Political: “Debate with Rivers” 1962 Campaign in Alaska, Tape number 1
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1962 December 14 (Folder 1782.18, Box 1782)
      Political “Debate with Rivers” 1962 Campaign in Alaska, Tape number 2
    - Mrs. Lowell Thomas, Jr. (Mary Tay), 1964 March 30 (Folder 1783.01, Box 1783)
      1. Recorded from Alaska
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. --political speech, 1964 May (Folder 1783.02, Box 1783)
      Juneau, Alaska, May 1964 Reel II
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. --political speech, 1964 May (Folder 1783.03, Box 1783)
      Juneau, Alaska, May 1964 Reel I
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. - Speech at Republican Convention 1964, 1964 July 13 (Folder 1783.04, Box 1783)
      1. Recorded by KCBS Radio at approximately 1830 hours
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1966 March (Folder 1783.05, Box 1783)
      Book revision notes for “Out of this World” (paperback). Transferred from wire to tape March 1966, reel number 2
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., 1966 March (Folder 1783.06, Box 1783)
      Book revision “Out of this World” for paperback edition. Recorded from wire to tape March 1966, number 3
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. book review, 1966 March (Folder 1783.07, Box 1783)
      On “Out of this World”. Also personal dictation. Recording from wire to tape March 1966, Reel II
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. interview, 1976 December 7 (Folder 1783.08, Box 1783)
      1. “This interview with Lowell, Jr. was sent out on our closed circuit newsfeed on Dec. 7th. Thought you might want a copy. Hope all is well with you. Bill” 2. CBS
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr., undated (Folder 1783.09, Box 1783)
      Lowell Thomas, Jr. recording made with “Jock” (Scotsman) at Kilimanjaro Saw mill Recording made in Tanganyika Colony near Kilimanjaro, with Sheikh Abdul Rashid at saw mill
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. from Ice Island near Pole, undated (Folder 1783.10, Box 1783)
      1. 80°N 55’ 170°E 2. In conversation via S/W with Mort Dank of CBS News
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. and Ralph Rivers, undated (Folder 1783.11, Box 1783)
      1. Radio - Television debate
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. (for G. Nicks) [Electra?], undated (Folder 1783.12, Box 1783)
      1. Reel 1 2. WNR - 12 News 3. Lowell Thomas show
    - Lowell Thomas, Jr. -near Honolulu, undated (Folder 1783.13, Box 1783)
      November 17
    - Goundam, undated (Folder 1783.14, Box 1783)
      1) Tay Thomas, Jr. talking with Fr. [French?] officer’s wife and daughter about nomads, camel patrol, nomad school 2) Reveille bugle - twice (2nd best) 3) Tay and Lowell Thomas, Jr. talking about Timbuktu in flight 4) After short blank tape, more talk about Tay’s navigation Talk to Don about film reels, April 24 and 26 through April 30, number 1, reel number 5
  - Subseries 1.10: Speeches, 1955 - 1974; 1.10; Boxes: 1783 - 1785
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1955 (Folder 1783.15, Box 1783)
      Made on a Webster Chicago tape recorder at above speed, Post marked April 15 - 1955 from Norwich, University, Northfield, Vermont
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1956 November 15 (Folder 1783.16, Box 1783)
      Bishop B. T. Rowe, Mount McKinley, Harry Carson, Speech about Alaska (live audience)
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1960 May 27 (Folder 1783.17, Box 1783)
      “The Golden Road to Samarkand” Valparaiso University 1960 Commencement Address
    - Speeches, Personalities: Olympic excerpts by Lowell Thomas 1961 (Folder 1783.18, Box 1783)
      Lowell Thomas, 1960 Winter Olympics, Excerpts from broadcast with intro, By Lowell Thomas
    - Speeches, Personalities: Reel I - Explorers Club 1961, 1964 April 26 (Folder 1784.01, Box 1784)
      Reel I - Explorers Club - Waldorf Hotel Lowell Thomas, H. V. Kaltenborn - Tribute to President Hoover Doctor Charles Hitchcock - Award President Hoover, Lowell Thomas
    - Speeches, Personalities: Reel III - Explorers Club, 1964 April 26 (Folder 1784.02, Box 1784)
      Reel III - Explorers Club - Waldorf Hotel Tom Gilliard continues (birds) Quentin Keynes (Lemurs)
    - Speeches, Personalities: Reel IV - Explorers Club, 1964 April 26 (Folder 1784.03, Box 1784)
      Explorer Club - Waldorf Hotel Quentin Keynes (continues) Captain Edward Beach - Commander Sub Triton - USN
    - Speeches, Personalities: Lowell Thomas, National Arts Club Reel 2, undated (Folder 1784.04, Box 1784)
      Lowell Thomas - address before members of National Arts Club in New York City Subject: “Road to Mandalay” Edited - spliced org. Ref. only - not suitable for broadcast
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1964 May (Folder 1784.05, Box 1784)
      Chicago Kent College of Law From Miriam A. Franklin 2033 MacVicar Avenue Topeka, Kansas
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1964 (Folder 1784.06, Box 1784)
      Commencement Address at Brigham Young University Salt Lake City
    - “An Evening With Lowell Thomas”, 1966 September 22 (Folder 1784.07, Box 1784)
      1. An address by Lowell Thomas at Macalester College 2. Part I
    - “An evening with Lowell Thomas” Part II, 1966 October 10 (Folder 1784.08, Box 1784)
      1. An address by Lowell Thomas at Macalester College 2. Part II recorded at Pawling, New York October 10, 1066 3. G. E. Nicks
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1968 (Folder 1784.09, Box 1784)
      22nd Anniversary WJOY Lowell Thomas speech in Burlington, VT - 6/11/68 Governor Hoff into to Lowell Thomas Vermont Day Reel 1 of 2 [Both reels were copied on Norelco cassette for LT’s personal review]
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1968 (Folder 1784.10, Box 1784)
      22nd Anniversary WJOY Lowell Thomas speech in Burlington, VT - 6/11/68 Governor Hoff into to Lowell Thomas Vermont Day Reel 2 of 2 [Both reels were copied on Norelco cassette for LT’s personal review]
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1968 (Folder 1784.11, Box 1784)
      Including others IRTS [International Radio & Television Society Foundation Inc.] Award luncheon - 5/14/68 Part 1
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1968 (Folder 1784.12, Box 1784)
      Including others IRTS [International Radio & Television Society Foundation Inc.] Award luncheon - 5/14/68 Part 2
    - NAB [National Association of Broadcasters] Convention, 1968 (Folder 1784.13, Box 1784)
      Remarks by Commissioner Cobb; Doctor Peale, President Johnson (surprise!) and speech by Lowell Thomas Chicago - 1968
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1970 February 16 (Folder 1784.14, Box 1784)
      Address to 53rd annual banquet Durham Chamber of Commerce, Durham, North Carolina
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, 1972 January 11 (Folder 1784.15, Box 1784)
      Impromptu speech made by Lowell Thomas “Nearly everything you say reminds you of something else”
    - Lowell Thomas Speech - Variety Club, 1973 February 14 (Folder 1784.16, Box 1784)
      Number 1, Opening Announcements and introductory speeches - reel 1 of 2
    - Lowell Thomas Speech, circa 1978 (Folder 1784.17, Box 1784)
      Lowell Thomas’s speech in Dayton, Ohio Town Hall
    - Lowell Thomas address, undated (Folder 1784.18, Box 1784)
      Chicago-Kent College of Law Lowell Thomas’s 50th anniversary as a Kent student
    - Lowell Thomas: New Knoxville Speech, undated (Folder 1785.01, Box 1785)
      British Islands, Ceylon[?], German Revolution, RAF
    - Speeches, undated (Folder 1785.02, Box 1785)
      Track number 1 - Lowell Thomas speech and P.M. bus. Saturday Sept. 15 Track number 2 - Morning and P.M. - cons., Bob Ross speech, Friday September 14, Saturday September 15
    - Richard Nixon Speech, 1968 D (Folder 1785.03, Box 1785)
      Accepting nomination of the Republican party for the 1968 Presidential Election
    - Inauguration Oath of Office and Inauguration speech of Governor Jay S. Hammond, 1974 December 2 (Folder 1785.04, Box 1785)
    - Congressman Walter Judd Speech, undated (Folder 1785.05, Box 1785)
      Dalai Lama No. 2
    - Congressman Walter Judd Speech, undated (Folder 1785.06, Box 1785)
      Dalai Lama, cold war, current events (live audience)
  - Subseries 1.11: Flight to South Pole, 1962 - 1963; 1.11; Box: 1787
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 November 27 (Folder 1785.07, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: Indonesia Opens: “Hello everybody-and to you Doug” Closes: …”So Long”…
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 3 (Folder 1785.08, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: Tahiti Opens: “Hello everybody, I’m still in Tahiti…..” Closes: ….”so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 5 (Folder 1785.09, Box 1785)
      Tape no. 8 Main speaker: Lowell Thomas Opens: “Hello everybody, you have all heard or read about Thor Heyderdahl, and the Kon Tiki…” Closes: …”and so long everybody”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 6 (Folder 1785.10, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas Opens: “Hello Doug…hello everybody” Closes: …”So long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 7 (Folder 1785.11, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: New Zealand Opens: “In New Zealand tonight Doug” Closes: …”So Long.”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 10 (Folder 1785.12, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: New Zealand, Mt. Cook Opens: “I’m surrounded by snow and ice tonight Doug” Closes: …“and a long run down Tasman glacier on skis, so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 11 (Folder 1785.13, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: New Zealand, Tasman Glacier Opens: “Hell everybody, some day when you want to get away from it all…” Closes: …”That five mile run down Tasman Glacier, So long:
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 12 (Folder 1785.14, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: Antarctica Opens: “Greetings from the bottom of the world” Closes: …”highest, windiest and coldest of all continents. So long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 13 (Folder 1785.15, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: near South Pole Opens: “Hello again from here near the South Pole” Closes: …”wherever you go, be prepared to walk home, so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 14 (Folder 1785.16, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: South Pole Opens: “Greetings again from down here near the South Pole”… Closes: “…he has a long red beard, -- so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 19 (Folder 1785.17, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: South Pole Opens: “Hello everybody, I suppose you have heard and read a good deal about the South Pole…” Closes: “So long until tomorrow”…”Having wonderful time, wish you were here.”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 20 (Folder 1785.18, Box 1785)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: South Pole Opens: “Still at the South Pole Doug.” Closes: “…right here at the South Pole, so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 21 (Folder 1786.01, Box 1786)
      Opens: “Hello Doug, good evening everybody” Closes: “….it was from a layer two hundred years old…So Long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 24 (Folder 1786.02, Box 1786)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas Opens: “I have an idea Doug” Closes: --“My thought for the day - so long” Repeat of “Santa Claus” [see 19.09 and 19.22]
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 25 (Folder 1786.03, Box 1786)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: South Pole Opens: “Before leaving the South Pole” Closes: ….”As I say - So long - to the South Pole”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 26 (Folder 1786.04, Box 1786)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: Australia Opens: “Hello Doug” - “Good evening everybody” Closes: …”by more than 300 Australian yachts - so long”
    - Lowell Thomas: Flight to South Pole, 1962 December 27 (Folder 1786.05, Box 1786)
      Main speaker: Lowell Thomas, Location: Australia Open: “I’m still in Australia Doug Hello Everybody” Close: “I’ll tell you tomorrow night - so long”